RG 178:001, Connecticut School for Boys
Connecticut State Library
Series 3. Canine Therapy, circa 1935, includes b/w photographs and staff newsletter
Series 4. Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1966, includes, articles about programs available at the school and laws affecting juvenile delinquents. Copies of photographs from clippings are placed with photographs in Box 7.
Series 5. Santori v. Maguder lawsuit, 1970, contains news clippings about a lawsuit between two policemen.
Series 6. Board of Public Welfare Investigation, 1930, includes testimony before Board of Trustees, Feb. 27, Mar 6 and 18; inmate files; misc. items; Julius Hadley report to Ernest Fuller; Trustees' rebuttal of Hadley Report.
Series 7. Sale of Land to City of Meriden, 1966-1967, includes property reports, appraisals; trustee meeting minutes; correspondence; legal documents; land easement excess area maps; other maps; aerial photos maps [J.F. Mulready Co.]
Series 8. New Highway Construction, 1966, contains maps and plans.
Series 9. Sale of Land to G.Fox Co., 1967, includes correspondence, trustee meeting minutes, correspondence and legal documents.
Series 10. Christiano Petition, 1922, contains a legal document petitioning the release of a boy from the school
Series 11. Superintendent, 1924-1966, includes quarterly reports, 1924 and Waterbury Republican correspondence, 1966.
Series 12. Written histories, 1856-1975, includes Griffin, Eliza C. "History and Development of the Connecticut School for Boys." Masters Thesis, School of Social Service Administration, Chicago, 1936; Portions of the State Auditors' report, 1974-1975; History Journal of the State Reform School, 1856-1874 compiled by various directors detailing events at the school.
Series 13. Student Publications 1897-1968, includes monthly newspaper: The Dawn, 1897; 1913; 1931; The Hilltop Hubbub, 1931-1968; Columbia Press Association 14th annual contest judging form, 1939; Graduation "programs", 1934-1952; Graduation program, 1960.
Series 14. Department of Education Survey, 1931, includes detailed analysis of educational programs at that time to identify strengths and weaknesses with recommendations for solutions to problems with the elementary education program and recommendations for a program to address needs of older boys not currently receiving satisfactory educational opportunities.
Series 15. Account Ledgers, 1929-1947, includes accounts receivable, 1929-1944 and petty cash, 1942-1946.
Series 16. Hospital Infirmary, 1960-1969, contains log book, 9/68-5/69 chronological by date
Series 17. Committee on Parole and Discharge, 1899-1922, contains correspondence, 1922 and minutes, 1899-1922.
Series 18. Executive Committee, 1894-1918, contains secretary's minutes.
Series 19. Board of Trustees, 1851-1969, includes by-laws, 1916; Annual reports to the General Assembly, 1854-1912 (sporadic copies); Minutes, 1854-1969
Series 20. Equipment Facilities, undated, contains Specifications for new building (poor condition) and Watkins Bros. presentation set of b/w photographs and pen and ink drawings of office equipment and furniture. Architectural drawings by E.C. Gardner of Springfield of Cottage A, n.d. (sent to conservation).
Series 21. Photographs, circa 1930-1968, includes b/w and color prints of various sizes sorted by topics including African-American inmates, Athletic events, Class days (graduation), Facilities buildings, Group portraits, Marching Bands, Miscellaneous unidentified, Negatives, Pageants parades; Recreational activities, Staff, Theatrical events, Vocational training, Winter (18 folders); Framed panoramic views of original building (2 items unboxed).
Series 22. Sound Recordings, 1959-1962, includes reel-to-reel magnetic tape of student productions and events including school chorus, 1959; Mikado, Act 2, 1960; Mikado, 1961; graduation, 1961; Oklahoma, 1962 (rehearsals and performance); 1 unboxed unidentified tape. 6 reels. NOTE: The State Library does not have a reel-to-reel tape recorder. Researchers must provide their own equipment.
Series 23. Scrapbooks, 1928-1970, contains primarily local newsclippings concerning events at the school including the 1930 investigation into abuse as well as later similar cases and labor-management issues
Series 24. Student Records, 1925-1973, includes roll books, population statistics, orientation and intake staffing notebook, runaways lists, and cash and withdrawal slips, and school registers.
Series 25. Memorandums, 1968-1973, includes information about staff policies and changes.
Series 26. Correspondence, 1954, contains a letter from juvenile courts.
Series 27. Miscellaneous, 1970-1971, includes Pamphlet on mental health talks and recreation center canteen cards.
Series 28. Case Files, circa 1900-1956 includes individual files on boys which include correspondence, intelligence test scores and parole placement information.
Series 29. Case History Books, 1854-1967, includes, individual inmate histories including personal statistics, admissions information, and discharge information compiled from case files. Location of original files unknown. Many records include admission officer's impressions and, in later records, the boy's own statement on his history and family background. The State Library did not receive vols. 26 and 31. Cumulative Index available for vols. 1-27.
Series 30. Daily Registers, 1921-1973, includes admissions and discharges by month with other statistical information.
Series 31. Cottage Staff Book, 1972, includes daily reports and assignments with incident reports.
Related Material
Researchers should also consult the Records of the Governor, RG 5 and Records of the Judicial Department, RG 3.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
State Reform School; Connecticut School for Boys (Meriden, Conn.)
Places:
Meriden (Conn)
Subjects:
Juvenile delinquents -- Rehabilitation -- Connecticut; Reformatories -- Connecticut; Male juvenile delinquents -- Rehabilitation -- Connecticut; Connecticut School for Boys (Meriden, Conn.) -- records and correspondence; Juvenile corrections -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Journals (accounts); Maps; Minutes; Newsletters; Photographs; Sound recordings
Restrictions on Access
Items in Series 1: Operations Manuals, Series 2: Old Burial Ground, Series 6: Board of Public Welfare Investigation, Series 10: Christiano Petition, Series 11: Superintendent, Series 14: Department of Education Survey, Series 15: Account Ledgers, Series 16: Hospital Infirmary, Series 17: Committee on Parole and Discharge, Series 18: Executive Committee, Series 19: Board of Trustees, Series 21: Photographs, Series 22: Sound Recordings, Series 24: Student Records, Series 28: Case Files, Series 29: Daily Registers and History Books, Series 30: Daily Registers and Series 31: Cottage Staff are restricted
Some items in Series 12: Written Histories and Series 13: Student Publications are restricted
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
All Series are Accession 1995-028 except for Series 13, Student Publications, which has Accessions 1995-028 and 2008-042; and Series 24, Student Records, which has Accessions 1995-028 and 2003-045.
- Series 1. Operations Manuals, circa 1970
  Restricted
  - Treatment Unit copy, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series 2. Old Burial Ground, 1855-1995
  - 1871-1986, Includes death certificates, news clippings, correspondence and Meriden Death Register (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Old Cemetery log, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1990 December 25-1995 December 31, undated, Includes newspaper clippings and lists of buried children (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 3. Canine Therapy, circa 1935
  - 1935, 10 photographs and newsletter (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 4. Newspaper Clippings, 1949-1966
  - 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 5. Santori v. Magruder lawsuit, 1970 November 3-25
  - (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series 6. Board of Public Welfare Investigation, 1930
  - Testimony, 1930 February 27
    - 1930 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - #1-15, 1930 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - #16-28, 1930 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of Trustees, 1930 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1930 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Inmate files, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14-26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Julius Hadley report to Ernest Fuller, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Trustees' rebuttal of Hadley Report, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series 7. Sale of Land to City of Meriden, 1966-1967
  - Property reports and appraisals, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Board of Trustees meetings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Legal documents, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Aerial photos and maps, 1967; J.F. Mulready Co. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Land and easement maps and excess area maps, 1966 April (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Other maps, 1966; J.F. Mulready Co. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Series 8. New Highway Construction, 1966
  - Maps and plans, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series 9. Sale of Land to G.Fox Co., 1967
  - (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Series 10. Christiano Petition, 1922
  - (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series 11. Superintendent, 1924-1966
  - Quarterly report, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Waterbury Republican correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series 12. Written Histories, 1856-1975
  - History journal of the State Reform School, 1856-1874; 1 volume (Box 2)
  - Thesis, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Auditor's report, 1975 August (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series 13. Student Publications, 1892-1968
  - 1995-028
    - The Saga, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Hilltop Annual, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - June Sunset, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Class Log, 1940-1952 (Box 2)
      - 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Dawn, 1897, 1913 (Box 2)
      See also Accession 2008-042 below.
      - 1897, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1913 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Hilltop Hubbub, 1931-1968 (Box 2)
      - Vol. 1-3, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 4-5, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 6-7, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 8-9, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 10-11, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 12-13, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 15, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 26, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 28-29, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 36, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - 1931 December 10-1939 February 15, 1 volume; Oversize
      - Graduation issues, 1950-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Columbia Scholastic Press Association, 14th annual contest, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Graduation program, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 2008-042
    - The Dawn, 1892-1906; 17 issues (Box 1)
      Consists of the following: 1892 August; 1893 May; 1893 November; 1893 December; 1894 January; 1894 February; 1894 March; 1894 April; 1894 May; 1894 June; 1894 July; 1894 September; 1894 November; 1894 December; 1905 November; 1906 November; 1906 December.
      Use copies of these issues are in Connecticut Documents [CSL call number Sch66d].
      See also Accession 1995-028 above.
- Series 14. Department of Education Survey, 1931
  - Surveys, 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- Series 15. Account Ledgers, 1929-1947
  - 1929 June-1945 June, 1 volume (Box 3)
  - 1942 July-1947 March, 1 volume (Box 3)
- Series 16. Hospital Infirmary, 1968-1969
  - Hospital infirmary log, 1968 September-1969 May; 1 volume (Box 3)
  - Medical log, 1963 March-1968 September; 2 volumes (Box 11)
- Series 17. Committee on Parole and Discharge, 1899-1922
  - Minutes, 1899-1922 (Box 3)
    - 1899 June-1915 July, 1 volume (Box 3)
    - 1915 October-1918 March, 1 volume (Box 3)
    - 1922 November, Includes one letter (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1918 May-1922 September (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Series 18. Executive Committee, 1894-1918
  - Minutes, 1894 April-1918 January (Box 4)
    - 1894 April-1907 April, 1 volume (Box 4)
    - 1907 July-1918 January, 1 volume (Box 4)
- Series 19. Board of Trustees, 1851-1969
  - Minutes, 1851-1969 (Box 4)
    - 1851 June-1923 July, 1 volume; Includes petition for creating the school, the act establishing the school, and list of donors (Box 4)
    - 1924 April-1949 June, 1 volume; Includes list of Board Members as of August 1943 (Box 4)
    - 1949 July-1969 December, 1 volume (Box 5)
  - By-laws, circa 1916 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reports to the General Assembly, 1854-1912 (Box 5)
    - 1854, 1857, 1865-1867, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1871-1872, 1874, 1874, 1882, 1891, 1893, 1895-1896 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1900, 1906, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series 20. Equipment Facilities, undated
  - Specifications for furniture and equipment in new building, undated (Box 6)
  - Watkins Brothers presentation of photographs of equipment and furniture, undated (Box 6)
  - Architechtural drawings of Cottage A, undated; Drawings by E.C. Gardner of Springfield Sent to conservation
- Series 21. Photographs, circa 1930-1968
  - African-American students (exclusively), undated; 4 photographs (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Athletic events, undated; 10 photographs (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Class days (graduation ceremonies), 1934, undated; 2 photographs (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Facilities and buildings, 1930-1968, undated; 88 photographs (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Group portraits, 1930-1964, undated; 22 photographs (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bands, undated; 2 photographs (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bands, undated; 3 photographs (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified, 1940, undated; 11 photographs (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Negatives, undated; 11 photographs (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pageants and parades, 1946-1947, undated; 28 photographs (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Recreational activities, circa 1930-1937; 40 photographs (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Staff, 1959-1966, undated; 11 photographs (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Theatrical events, 1959-1967, undated; 62 photographs (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Theatrical (oversize), undated; 3 photographs (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Vocational training, undated; 3 photographs (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Winter, 1936, undated; 15 photographs (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Prints, undated; 18 photographs (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Halloween party-Cottage G, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Panoramic views of original building, 1932; 2 items
- Series 22. Sound Recordings, 1959-1962
  - School chorus, 1959 June 19 (Box 8)
  - Graduation, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Mikado (Box 8)
    - 1960 June (Box 8)
    - 1961 (Box 8)
  - Oklahoma, 1962 June (Box 8)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8)
- Series 23. Scrapbooks, 1928-1970; Oversize
- Series 24. Student Records, 1925-1973
  - 1995-028
    - Roll books, 1957-1963, 1965-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Population statistics, 1945-1973 (Box 9)
      - 1945 June-1952 December (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - 1953 January-1957 December (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 1956 January-1963 December (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - 1964 January-1968 December, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 1969 January-1973 June (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Orientation and intake staff notebook, 1970 January-1972 October (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Runaways list, 1940-1973 (Box 9)
      - 1940-1950 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 1950-1960 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 1960-1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 1970 May 22-1972 December 26 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 1973 January 1-June 7 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Cash withdrawal slips, 1967 May 23-1971 July 8 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 2003-045
    - School registers, 1925-1964
      - 1925-1930 (Box 1)
      - 1931-1932 (Box 2)
      - 1933-1940 (Box 3)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 4)
      - 1941-1943 (Box 5)
      - 1943-1945 (Box 6)
      - 1945-1947 (Box 7)
      - 1947-1949 (Box 8)
      - 1949-1952 (Box 9)
      - 1952-1954 (Box 10)
      - 1954-1956 (Box 11)
      - 1956-1962 (Box 12)
      - 1962-1964 (Box 13)
- Series 25. Memorandums, 1968-1973
  - 1968 February 26-1970 August 19 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1972 April 21-1973 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series 26. Correspondence, 1954 Oct 19
  - (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Series 27. Miscellaneous, 1970-1971
  - Recreation center canteen cards, 1970 April 10-1971 July 12 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Mental Health Talks from the Hartford Courant and Institute of Living, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series 28. Case Files, circa 1900-1956
  arranged by case number
  - 8197-10198 (Box 12)
  - 9706-9831 (Box 13)
  - 9836-9957 (Box 14)
  - 9958-10048 (Box 15)
  - 10050-10130 (Box 16)
  - 10131-10186 (Box 17)
  - 10189-10246 (Box 18)
  - 2-4-1S--2-4-153M (Box 19)
- Series 29. Case History Books, 1854-1967
  - Index to Case History Books, Index cards
    - Prior to 1928
      - A-Bor (Box 20)
      - Box-Clark, A (Box 21)
      - Clark, J-Die (Box 22)
      - Dil-Fr (Box 23)
      - Frankl-Hanl (Box 24)
      - Hans-Ke (Box 25)
      - Keel-Lud (Box 26)
      - Lun-Mid (Box 27)
      - Mil-Parke (Box 28)
      - Pars-Roe (Box 29)
      - Roh-Smith, C (Box 30)
      - Smith, F-Von (Box 31)
      - Wal-Zo (Box 32)
    - 1928-Closing
      - Aa-Bz (Box 33)
      - Cag-Doz (Box 34)
      - Dr-Harr (Box 35)
      - Has-Leg (Box 36)
      - Leg-My (Box 37)
      - Na-Ros (Box 38)
      - Ross-Tre (Box 39)
      - Tri-Z (Box 40)
  - History books, 1854-1967
    - Vol. 1, 1-325, 1854-1860
    - Vol. 2, 326-769, 1860-1865
    - Vol. 3, 800-1233, 1865-1867
    - Vol. 4, 1234-1659, 1867-1871
    - Vol. 5, 1661-2088, 1871-1873
    - Vol. 6, 2089-2504, 1873-1876
    - Vol. 7, 2505-2923, 1876-1879
    - Vol. 8, 2924-3340, 1879-1882
    - Vol. 9, 3341-3752, 1882-1884
    - Vol. 10, 3753-4176, 1884-1887
    - Vol. 11, 4177-4594, 1887-1889
    - Vol. 12, 4595-5011, 1889-1892
    - Vol. 13, 5012-5431, 1892-1894
    - Vol. 14, 5432-5851, 1894-1896
    - Vol. 15, 5852-6267, 1896-1899
    - Vol. 16, 6286-6685, 1899-1902
    - Vol. 17, 6686-7105, 1902-1905
    - Vol. 18, 7106-7520, 1905-1907
    - Vol. 19, 7521-7942, 1907-1909
    - Vol. 20, 7943-8374, 1909-1912
    - Vol. 21, 8375-8826, 1912-1914
    - Vol. 22, 8827-9353, 1914-1917
    - Vol. 23, 9354-9902, 1917-1918
    - Vol. 24, 9903-10426, 1918-1921
    - Vol. 25, 10427-10952, 1921-1923
    - Vol. 27, 11479-12029, 1926-1928
    - Vol. 28, 12030-12622, 1928-1932
    - Vol. 29, 12623-12873, 1932-1933
    - Vol. 30, 12874-13124, 1933-1934
    - Vol. 32, 13376-13624, 1936-1938
    - Vol. 33, 13625-13875, 1938-1940
    - Vol. 34, 13876-14124, 1940-1942
    - Vol. 35, 14125-14374, 1942-1943
    - Vol. 36, 14375-14624, 1943-1945
    - Vol. 37, 14625-14876, 1945-1946
    - Vol. 38, 14877-15126, 1946-1949
    - Vol. 39, 15127-15373, 1949-1951
    - Vol. 40, 15387-15642, 1951-1953
    - Vol. 41, 15643-15901, 1953-1955
    - Vol. 42, 15902-16161, 1955-1956
    - Vol. 43, 16162-16428, 1956-1958
    - Vol. 44, 16429-16712, 1958-1959
    - Vol. 45, 16713-16961, 1959-1960
    - Vol. 46, 16962-17214, 1960-1962
    - Vol. 47, 17215-17465, 1962-1963
    - Vol. 48, 17466-17717, 1963-1965
    - Vol. 49, 17718-18004, 1965-1966
    - Vol. 50, 18005-18168, 1966-1967
    - Case History Books Index, undated; 1 volume
- Series 30. Daily Registers, 1921-1973
  - 1921-1948, 1 volume
  - 1949-1967, 1 volume
  - 1967-1973, 1 volume
- Series 31. Cottage Staff Book, 1972; 1 volume